残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても 私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっとくれるもの 求めることに夢中で 運命さえまだ知らない 痛い気な瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使の手で 窓辺からやがて飛び立つ
ほとばしる熱いパッドスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
神話になれ
神話を飛んでいる
kind of confrontation, aren't they, Shinji?
Don't you have any spine at all?
I'm sorry, I...
There you go again!
Why do you always have to punish yourself
for everything?
There, there, that's just Shinji's way, you know.
It's so easy for you just to accept
his pathetic habits, isn't it?
But don't you think you've been too easy on him lately?
Have I?
Maybe you and Kaji have hooked up again,
but the fact that you're happy doesn't mean
that you can just ignore the welfare of the rest of us!
Look, there's nothing going on between me and Kaji.
Hey, Katsuragi,
I found a bar that serves a decent drink.
How about tonight? Bye!
I've never been around anyone
who's been involved in such a totally indecent relationship.
And you're supposed to be our guardian?
What a hypocrite! It's disgusting!
Me type harmonics test, all systems green.
Projected adjustment values have been cleared.
You're looking pretty worn to the bone,
Major Katsuragi.
There's reasons why I'm worn.
Private ones.
Kaji's bone.
Shut your face!
Anyway, how's the third child doing?
Just take a look.
Oh.
Wow.
I bet knowing this will boost his confidence a little.
Can you hear me, Shinji?
Uh-huh.
Oh, hi, Misato.
So how are my test scores looking?
Great!
You're number one!
Oh, it's not just that I lost.
It's that he beat us so easily.
He beat us so easily that it's really pissing me off.
Oh, he's so great.
He's so wonderful.
He's so awesome.
Shinji, he's our hero.
And he used to be a zero.
Okay, so that just makes our job a little easier, right?
But it also means that the two of us will have to be doing double time just so that we're not left behind.
I'm leaving.
Next stop is Seisho Caboose.
Seisho Caboose.
Convenient for the Bashar.
Used books and video game stores.
Yeah.
Five minutes until the evacuation of the Western District can be completed.
The target is advancing slowly at approximately 2.5 kilometers per hour.
You're late, Major.
Sorry.
What's going on?
The Fuji Observation Center's...
Never detected it.
It just suddenly appeared right above us.
The pattern is orange.
No AT field detected.
What is that thing?
A new kind of angel?
Unknown.
The Magi are withholding their judgment on that.
Damn.
Another situation like this at Commandikari is not here again.
Can you all hear me?
I've sent you all of the known target data.
That's literally all we know right now.
Approach it carefully and observe its reactions.
And if possible, try to lure it outside of the city.
I want you all to back up each other.
Is that understood?
Yes, ma'am!
But don't you think that Shinji ought to be taking the point position?
Huh?
Well, it's only right that a job like this should go to the highest rated, bravest, number
one synchro ratio holder of them all, don't you think?
Or could it be that you don't feel up to that Shinji?
I didn't do it.
In fact, I'll show you how it ought to be done, Asuka.
What was that?
Will the two of you cut it out?
Oh, gee.
Uh, didn't you tell me, Misato, that I was number one?
Well, yeah, but I...
And after all, combat's a man's job.
You're a show of a piglet!
But Unit 2 will back him off.
Unit 0 will back up as well.
I don't believe these kids.
Shinji's hormones are kicking in, aren't they?
I'm gonna have to chew him out when he gets back.
Of course.
You're a model guardian.
Ayanami, Asuka, are you in your positions yet?
Not yet.
You know it, Ava can't move that fast, you twit!
Scheisse!
Are you there?
Alright, I'll stop it myself.
It vanished!
Status!
Pattern blue!
Angel, confirm!
It's right beneath Uniguan!
I was a...
a shuttle!
What the hell is this?
This can't be happening!
It's Shinji!
Get out of there!
Shinji!
Mikari!
You idiot!
Get their ass again!
Misato!
What's going on?
Help me!
Misato!
He jacked that plug!
Get him out of there!
No response!
It's not working!
Can you hear me?
Misato!
Shinji!
Asuka, right!
Rescue unit one, hurry!
What's the point in only getting A's on tasks and not the real world?
It's gone again!
Asuka, watch the screen!
The shadow!
Oh!
The whole city is sinking!
Asuka!
Rei!
Pull back!
Get out of there!
Whoa!
Wait!
Unibund and Shinji are still in there!
This is an order!
Withdraw now!
Major Katsuragi must feel terrible!
They reeled Shinji's umbilical cable back in but the other end was missing then without power
There's not much energy left in the internal batteries if Shinji doesn't waste it groping blindly in the dark
If he stays in the most minimal life support mode, then he can survive for 16 hours
The UN forces have surrounded the shadow
Movement it hasn't moved it stopped spreading once it passed a diameter of 600 meters
Speaking of which is there a reason for moving all those ground troops in there. They're there to help us apply pressure
Well taking matters into his own hands defying operations
I guess he got what he was asking for just because he got a little better score than mine
Why'd you have to go and try to show me how it ought to be done?
What oh were my comments about Shinji pissing you off wonder girl I?
Wonder do you only pilot an Ava for the praise of others?
What the hell are you talking about? I don't need to have anybody's approval, but my own
Cut it out you two
Oscar's right. He acted arbitrarily and without consulting anyone
So I guess I'll just have to punish him when he comes back
To be you this yet
I never thought that doing nothing could beat this exhausting
Uh
still nothing but white noise no radar data or sonar reflections
it's been 12 hours since i switched to life support mode
my life will end in four or five hours i'm hungry so that shadow is actually the angel's body
correct it's 680 meters in diameter with a thickness of three nanometers sustained within
that ultra thin space is an inverted at field inside of that field is a region of space that
can only be defined by abstract mathematics a sea of dirac it could be another universe
what about the sphere it disappears when the imaginary circuit of the body closes
this implies that the object in the sky is a kind of shadow so the black shadow that swallowed unit
one is the real target and there's no way we can fight it
the water's getting cloudy the purification system is breaking down
it smells in here
blood this light smells like blood
it's not going right in this place let me out
why can't i open this lock open up let me out
he's not going to tell me what's going on he's not all
oscar and army beat skull
father
please
someone help me
you're gonna blow the shadow up
i'm afraid it's the only possibility that might work
the plan is to drop all 992 existing n2 mines into the target center while simultaneously activating the at fields of both remaining avas in such a way as to disrupt the hypothetical circuit that encloses the angels pocket interior if we concentrate enough explosive power during that same microsecond we could destroy the angel along with the dirac sea that makes up its body
but the damage to eva would be
our priority is to get the eva back even if it has to be destroyed in the process
now wait a second under these conditions the pilot's life is irrelevant
it's your responsibility if shinji's lost masato you seem to have forgotten that
i've forgotten that
then why in the hell are you and commander ikari so worried about recovering unit one
what's so special about it
you've been given all the information major
that's a bull
miss auto
just trust me
i'm taking command of this entire operation effective immediately
forward all flights to kansai international airport
contact air control
second impact
the instrumentality project
adam
there's so many secrets that i'm in the dark about
who's that
who
shinji akari
that that's me
i am you
this self incorporates another self
the self has always been composed of two selves
two
yes
the self which is observed and the self which observes itself
to expound
there is the shinji akari that exists in your mind
the shinji akari in misato katsuragi's mind
the shinji akari in asuka soryu's mind
the shinji akari in rei ayinami's mind
and the shinji akari in gendo akari's mind
all are different shinji akari's but each of them is a true shinji akari
what you fear is the shinji akari's who exist in the minds of others
i'm just afraid of being hated
you are afraid of being hurt
who is bad
father is
the father who deserted us
no i'm the one who's bad
there you go again you're always apologizing
do you really think it's your fault
i'm worthless
no you just believe that you're worthless shinji
don't you trust your own father
i thought i hated my father but now i'm not sure
that was good work shinji
my father called me by my name
i was praised by my father
will you live the rest of your life regurgitating and redigesting those few pleasant memories
if i trust their words it's enough enough to keep me alive
even though you know you're deceiving yourself
everybody does it that's how everyone survives
if you will not accept that you are capable of initiating change within yourself
you will be unable to continue
this world is filled with too much pain and suffering to keep going on
for example you can't swim
humans aren't made to float
this is self-deception
i don't care what you want to call it
you have been shutting your eyes and covering your ears
making yourself blind and deaf to that which you wish to avoid
his sister was injured during the incident
who cares what the others say
leave
see you're running away from the reality again
no i don't want to hear this
no one can justify their existence by linking their happiest moments into a kind of rosary
in particular
i cannot
what's wrong with doing something i want to do
why won't you leave me alone
the entry plug energy reserve should be reaching their expiration point about now
the plug suits life support system will be getting closer to redline
we'll advance the schedule by twelve minutes
let's do it while there's a possibility that shinji's still alive
father don't you want me
don't you want me
father
it was yourself that you ran away from
that's right he may be guilty of killing his own wife
he killed his own wife
no mother was smiling
shinji you did something very important today
shinji you must not run away
you've got to do your best
i hate this place
i hate this loneliness
i mean no
the heat system and the oxygen are giving out
i'm cold
the suit is giving out too
it's so cold
this is the end
so tired
of everything
the
mother
is this enough
well that's good for you
Well, that's good for you.
Both Avas are in possession and standing by.
AT fields are ready to generate.
Roger.
T-minus 60 seconds to mine drop.
What the hell is that?
What's going on?
We don't know!
All of our meters and gauges are going off the scale.
But we haven't done anything yet.
You think it could be shinji?
It's impossible.
Uni-1's power level must be at zero.
My god.
Is that what I'm piloting?
God in heaven.
What kind of monster have we made this from?
I know that the Avas are more than just copies of the first angel.
But what is Nerve going to do with them?
What is Nerve going to do with the Avas once all the angels have been destroyed?
I have not yet.
Let's do it.
What does it mean?
It could be just we will.
Well, we will do the similar valleys and rise in the minerals.
What can you do completely
should I leave the cushion behind me?
を 銘 chase sc CNN
Shindy, Shindy, are you all right?
I just wanted to see them one more time.
Weren't you going to punish him?
I've never seen the Ava looking as horrifying as it did today.
Are the Avas really on our side?
Or do they hate us?
There's something else.
I think that Major Katsuragi may suspect something.
Let her be, at least for now.
If Rei or Shinji were to learn about the Ava's secrets,
they'd never forgive us.
You can rest today.
We'll take care of everything.
But I'm feeling just fine now.
Well, that's good for you.
It still smells like blood.
Good night.
Fair 003 years ago.
Thank you.
My love for you.
Here's what I mess.
Thank you.
For all I want, for all I want, should I do?
In other worlds, with this feature.
In other worlds, I love you.
Disaster strikes when AVA Unit 4 vanishes during its activation test,
taking the entire second branch of Nerve with it.
As the Sele Council attempts to adjust their plans,
the Fourth Child is selected in anticipation of the activation of AVA Unit 3.
Next episode, The Fourth Child.
The Fourth Child.